Gauray Tamhan

gaurav.tamhan@gmail.com | (770) 570-6895 | www.gauravtamhan.com

Profile

Frontend developer with 3+ years of experience building and maintaining both web and mobile apps. Passionate about UX and design, backed by experience in industry and team projects. Seeking a full-time role starting in Summer 2020.

Skills

Development: HTML/SASS, JavaScript, React, Vue, Redux, Styled Components, D3, Node, MySQL

Practices: Agile Development, SCRUM, Git, RESTful APIs, JWT, Responsive Web Design

Design Tools: Photoshop, Sketch, Adobe XD, InVision

Experience

Graduate Research Assistant in CSPAV at Georgia Tech

August 2019 - December 2019

- Worked with lead designer to translate wireframes into a functional product given budget, resource, and time constraints.
- Lead development of a data visualization app using React, Mapbox, D3, and JWT for authentication.

Frontend Developer at Fitspot, Atlanta

May 2018 - July 2019

- Designed and implemented 4 new features for the primary customer web portal.
- Built and deployed a mobile-first designed, progressive web app using React, Redux/Thunk.
- Built reusable and scalable modules, performed bug fixes, and conducted code reviews.

Software Engineering Intern at JDA Software Inc, Roswell

January 2016 - August 2017

• Developed, maintained, and tested a full-stack web application that handles workforce management of large scale retailers using C#, SQL, and Visual Studio.

Projects

React Native Cross Platform App

April 2019

• Built a small scale marketplace that allows users to post, manage, and complete tasks using React Native, Node, Firebase, Expo, and PayPal API.

Home Depot FirstPhone Redesign

August 2018

• Partnered with Home Depot Store Ops team to design an alternate solution for their in-store enterprise tool. Conducted UX research and crafted personas, information architecture, and interactive prototypes for user testing.

Data Visualization Tool

May 2017

• Built a data visualization tool using D3 and College Scorecard data to assist high school students research college admission statistics.

Education

Georgia Institute of Technology

• M.S. Human Computer Interaction

May 2020

• B.S. Computer Science